RESUME

PERSONAL DATA

Name: Lalith Nag, Sharan Gururaj

Mobile: +49 176 35881991

E-Mail: <u>lalith.sharan@ovgu.de</u>

Date, Place-of-Birth: 27.02.1993, Chennai (India)



I'm a medical systems engineer focused on deep learning and computer vision for healthcare applications – in particular registration, segmentation and depth-reconstruction.

CURRENT POSITION

Apr 2019 to present Master's Thesis Student

Research Project "Computer-based Quantification of

Reconstructive Mitral Valve Surgery" at Mannheim University of Applied Sciences and Heidelberg University Hospital, Germany

Depth estimation in stereo-endoscopy using deep learning for application in mitral valve reconstruction surgery. Frameworks

used: Tensorflow, PyTorch, OpenCV

EDUCATION

Apr 2017 to present Master's Degree, M.Sc. in Medical Systems Engineering

Otto von Guericke University, Magdeburg (Germany) Specialisation: Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Computer-assisted Surgeries & Interventions Current grade: 1.6/4 (Max.: 1.0, Min. passing: 4.0)

Jul 2010 to May 2014 Bachelor's Degree, B.E. in Biomedical Engineering

Manipal Institute of Technology, Karnataka (India)

Specialisation: Pattern Recognition, Medical Image and Signal

Processing

Grade: 8.69/10 (Max.: 10.0, Min. passing: 5.0)

Jun 2008 to May 2010 All India Senior Secondary School Certificate

Central Board of Secondary Education, Chennai (India) Specialisation: Computer Science, Mathematics, Physics,

Chemistry

Grade: 89.6% (Max.: 100%, Min. passing: 33%)

PROJECTS

Apr 2018 to Jul 2018 Landmark Detection in Echocardiography

Automatic segmentation of mitral valve in 3D using U-Net architecture- pre-processing with MevisLab & ParaView.

Oct 2017 to Jun 2018 **Depth-mapping for stereo-endoscopy**

Stereo-reconstruction using computer vision techniques from surgical data, implemented using OpenCV libraries on C++.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Oct 2018 to Mar 2019 Internship

Research Project "Computer-based Quantification of

Reconstructive Mitral Valve Surgery" at Mannheim University of Applied Sciences and Heidelberg University Hospital, Germany

Depth estimation in stereo-endoscopy using deep learning for application in mitral valve reconstruction surgery. Frameworks

used: Tensorflow, PyTorch, OpenCV

Jan 2018 to Sep 2018 Student Research Assistant

Otto Von Guericke Universität, Magdeburg (Germany) Support of research in the *Computer Assisted Surgeries* research group; multi-modal registration of MRI & US data, medical visualisation using MeVisLab + python, 3D slicer.

Nov 2014 to Mar 2017 Manager-Strategy

eHelium Advisory Service Private Limited, Chennai (India) Market analysis, identifying gaps & opportunities in building a scalable online education platform for entry-level talent pool in

Indian service sector.

Jan 2014 to May 2014 Trainee

Institute of Nuclear Medicine & Allied Sciences, Delhi (India)
Bachelor thesis on *Cognitive State Assessment using EEG*Signals. Developed a classifier to assess cognitive-state using 14-channel EEG signals in a war-like multi-tasking scenario.

SKILLS

Software: Python (Keras+Tf, PyTorch), C++, OpenCV, MeVis Lab, 3D Slicer, MS Office

Languages: **English**: Proficient in Speaking, Writing (C2)

Deutsch: Good in Speaking, Writing (B2), **Tamil**: Native proficiency

Heidelberg, 26.05.2019

glauch